HIMANSHU GAUTAM

9910835593 • himanshugnsit@qmail.com • https://linkedin.com/in/h1manshu • Bengaluru

Summary

I consider myself a bit leader, a bit learner and a bit of explorer. Passionate about solving complex problems and optimizing systems for efficiency and performance. Proven experience in Data Engineering and ETL platform development.

Experience

Hevo Data

Software Development Engineer

10/2021 - Present

hevodata.com

- · Developed, optimized, and maintained backend services in Java, ensuring system performance and stability.
- Utilized AWS for cloud services, managing services like EC2, S3, and RDS.
- Focused on the Destinations (Load) side of ETL pipeline product, contributing to its development and improvement.
- Employed Kafka for message queuing and managed MySQL and Redis databases.
- Monitored system performance and metrics using Grafana and InfluxDB.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver robust and scalable software solutions.

Thales India (Guavus)

Gurgaon, India
Technical Leader

01/2019 - 10/2021

guavus.com, sqlstream.com

- Designed and implemented large-scale data processing systems using Spark and Hadoop.
- · Managed and scaled Kubernetes clusters to ensure optimal resource utilization and high availability.
- · Developed applications in Java and Scala, following best practices to write clean and efficient code.
- · Utilized Ansible for configuration management, automating routine system administration tasks.
- Collaborated closely with data science teams to optimize data processing and ML pipelines
- Driving design discussions and conducting scrum meetings in addition to technical responsibilities. Also working on smooth technical onboarding and mentoring my juniors.

Airtel X Labs Gurgaon, India
Software Engineer 08/2018 - 07/2019

Airtel x-Labs Product Engineering

Backend engineering: Java application under service oriented architecture. Had ownership of components related to billing and customer data

• Working closely with product teams at Airtel x-labs in developing and managing backend-services built in java based tech stack for multiple products. Engineering solutions for large-scale business problems by developing, designing and documenting APIs and code base followed by going live with features & improvements in CI-CD environment.

InfoEdge (naukri.com)

Noida Area, India
Software Engineer

07/2017 - 08/2018

naukri.com

- Implemented and deployed on production automated screening of "About Me" section using machine learning based algorithms (accuracy above 93% fraud and abuse detection).
- Integrated ELK (Elastic, Logstash and Kibana) stack with Filebeat and Kafka, a Log Monitoring Tool which helps in visualizing all application logs
 making Root Cause Analysis of various problems very easy with alerting.

Education

Netaji Subhas Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Engineering

01/2013 - 01/2017

Delhi Public School, Dwarka

High School Diploma Date period

Skills